Some thing has found us.
Cloverfield is a action, thriller, science fiction film directed by Matt Reeves.
Five young New Yorkers throw their friend a going-away party the night that
a monster the size of a skyscraper descends upon the city.
Told from the point of view of their video camera, the film is a document of their
attempt to survive the most surreal, horrifying event of their lives.
Marlena, played by Lizzy Caplan.
Lily, played by Jessica Lucas.
Hud, played by T.J. Miller.
Rob Hawkins, played by Michael Stahl-David.
Jason Hawkins, played by Mike Vogel.
Beth McIntyre, played by Odette Annable.
Cloverfield is a 2008 American found footage monster horror film
directed by Matt Reeves and written by Drew Goddard.
It stars Lizzy Caplan, Jessica Lucas, T.J.
Miller (in his film debut), Michael Stahl-David, Mike Vogel, and Odette Yustman.
In the film, six friends attempt to flee from a
monster that attacks New York City.
Development began when producer J.
Abrams started conceptualizing a monster film and enlisted Neville
Page to design the eventual creature, called Clover.
In February 2007, the project was secretly greenlit by
Paramount Pictures and produced by Abrams's Bad Robot.
Principal photography took place in Los Angeles and New York City in 2007.
The project had several working titles, including Slusho, Cheese, and Greyshot.
As part of a viral marketing campaign, a teaser trailer was released
ahead of screenings of Transformers (2007) without a title.
The final title was revealed in a second teaser trailer
attached to screenings of Beowulf (2007).
With limited pre-release details, it garnered online speculation, including forums and
websites dedicated to uncovering hidden information about the film.
Several tie-ins, including a prequel manga series, were
released as part of the marketing campaign.
Cloverfield was released on January 18, 2008, and received generally positive reviews from
critics, who praised Reeves's direction and the cinéma vérité style narrative.
It earned $172 million worldwide at the box office against a $25 million budget.
It is the first installment of the Cloverfield franchise, followed by 10
Cloverfield Lane in 2016 and The Cloverfield Paradox in 2018.
A direct sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of quarantine, monster,
chaos, skyscraper, supernatural.
The tone is intense and thought_provoking and mind_bending.